Guide to the Whirlwind Hill Farm Papers (1940-1977)
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Whirlwind Hill Farm papers
1940-1977
OSB MSS 9
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
5.4
(12 boxes)
Correspondence, business and financial records, writings and printed material concerning the operation of Whirlwind Hill Farm, in Wallingford, Connecticut. The material documents James M. Osborn's breeding and marketing of purebred Holstein dairy cattle, and the status of dairy farming in the Northeast in the 1940s and 1950s.
Osborn, James M. (James Marshall), 1906-1976
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of James Marshall Osborn, 1976.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH
James Marshall Osborn, literary historian, founder of the James Marshall and Marie-Louise Osborn Collection at Yale University, and Holstein cattle breeder, was born in Cleveland, Ohio in 1906. He graduated from Wesleyan University in 1928, and joined the investment advisory department of Guaranty Trust in New York. The next year, he married Marie-Louise Montgomery, a graduate of Vassar.
In 1932 Osborn left Guaranty Trust to study for a Master's degree in English at Columbia University. Two years later, the Osborns moved to England with their two sons, and James began to work toward a B.Litt degree at Oxford University. While at Oxford, Osborn pursued his interest in eighteenth-century literary history and began to acquire the literary and historical manuscripts that would form the core of the Osborn Collection.
Osborn was appointed Research Associate in English at Yale University in 1938; he held the position until the time of his death. He was named Adviser on Seventeenth Century Manuscripts to the Yale Library in 1954, and in 1963, when he began the transfer of his collection to Yale, became the first curator of the Osborn Collection.
Osborn's publications include The Autobiography of Thomas Whythorne (1961); an edition of Joseph Spence's Observations, Anecdotes and Characters (1966); and Young Philip Sidney (1972).
In addition to his scholarly activities, Osborn was also a noted dairy cattle breeder and promoter of Holsteins from 1940 to 1960. He received the D.Litt from Oxford University in 1968, and was named Curator Emeritus of the Osborn Collection in 1972. James Marshall Osborn died in New Haven on October 17, 1976.
Scope and Contents
Twice between 1940 and 1960, James Marshall Osborn (JMO) built herds of purebred Holstein dairy cattle to recognized excellence at Whirlwind Hill Farm in Wallingford, Connecticut. The farm was known throughout the world for its breeding of pedigreed bulls, by which, through the process of artificial insemination, tens of thousands of dairy cattle were sired worldwide.
As a result of the diverse background Professor Osborn brought to the dairy business, this collection represents a source material for scholars pursuing more than just a study of the cattle trade. Decisions made on the farm, based upon certain government regulations and taxing policies, are recorded within for the economist and the land-use student. As a literary scholar and writer himself, Mr. Osborn made frequent observations upon the nature of scholarship in a pastoral setting. His bibliographical record of The Holstein Handbook sheds light not only on his own writing for the trade, but on the whole scope of the dairy market of that era as well. Finally, Mr. Osborn has saved for us all of his advertising materials which produced the success of the farm over the period of 20 years. They prove useful not only as a marketing record, but as the best resource for a study of the blood lines of his cattle.
The papers are divided into six categories, beginning with a compilation of the available accounts of the farm and its progress from contemporary journals, newspaper articles, diaries and the like. It is suggested to the researcher that this is the first place to start for the reason that quick familiarity with important names and dates can be attained.
This secondary source material is backed up with box 2, a compilation of articles and pamphlets on the status of dairy farming at the time. Once acquainted with the political, social and temporal environment of the collection, the researcher finds the original source material in boxes 3-17 more meaningful.
Osborn saved all of his correspondence, and much of it ran through more than the life of the farm with certain individuals. The researcher will find that the correspondence supplements the material endeavors recorded in the source material of boxes 8-17. Osborn was constantly called to participate in various cattlemen's associations and organizations. While the researcher can find the product of his involvement in box 8, it is the correspondence that indicates the nature of his intent, and often portrays the Homeric difficulties Osborn faced in his dual role as a farmer and a world class scholar of English literature. For a man who professed to have so little time, however, Osborn did manage to record a good deal of the difficulty through his stenographer.
From the early stages of the farm development on, Osborn advertised with a budget disproportionate to his size. That this strategy paid off is seen by the fact that the 1959 dispersal sale was the largest ever, with journalists calling it the cattle event of the year. Regular readers of dairy magazines had been kept apprised throughout of the growth of the herd into high-producing Holsteins and bulls sought the world over for their sire-power. And it was not long before the advertising of other dairymen began to piggyback upon the goodwill of the name of the Whirlwind Hill Farm. Cattlemen who had bought blood line cattle from Osborn testified in print that "Our Whirlhills Pay the Bills."
As both evidence of an effective public relations strategy, and as direct source material in the geneological history of the Whirlwind Hill Herds, advertising records are filed in box 9. It is accompanied by the original photographs of the cattle and the farm that were used in advertisments, catalogues, and circulars, found in boxes 9-11.
Boxes 12-17 contain the financial records of the farm, random proprietary correspondence, and miscallaneous documents of the farm's growth.
Cattle breeds; Cattle -- Breeding -- Connecticut; Dairy cattle; Dairy farming -- Connecticut; Whirlwind Hill Farm; Osborn, James M. (James Marshall), 1906-1976
- Works about the farm, Series I
  Scope and Contents
  Works about the farm by James Marshall Osborn and
  Marie-Louise Osborn, Newspaper articles about the farm,
  Photos and miscellaneous.
  - James Marshall Osborn (Box 1, Folder 1)
    1948 Jan 3, Holstein-Friesian World
    "The 1948 Outlook"
  - James Marshall Osborn (Box 1, Folder 2)
    1948 Jul 3, Holstein-Friesian World
    Advertises "Thank you" for response to
    "The Holstein Handbook". Accompanied by
    advertising circular for "The Holstein
    Handbook".
  - James Marshall Osborn (Box 1, Folder 3)
    1948 Oct 19, New Haven County Farm Bureau
    Letter to New Haven Board of Aldermen who were
    investigating price of milk.
    Signature of Edward P. Rowland, Chairman, NHCFB.
  - James Marshall Osborn (Box 1, Folder 4)
    1948 Nov 18, Hartford Courant
    Editorial by Mr. Osborn.
    1948 Nov 13, Hartford Courant
    Letter to the editor explaining how cows' names
    are derived.
  - James Marshall Osborn (Box 1, Folder 5)
    8 Jan 1949
    Notes for speech for annual meeting of New Jersey
    Holstein-Friesian Co-operative Association.
    Accompanied by news release.
  - James Marshall Osborn (Box 1, Folder 6)
    1943-49
    Scrapbook of clippings about the farm.
  - James Marshall Osborn (Box 1, Folder 7)
    [1955], WTIC radio program
    2 records
    Talks about cattle breeding and the Eastern States
    Exhibition.
  - James Marshall Osborn (Box 1, Folder 8)
    1956 Sep-Oct, New England Holstein Bulletin
    "Connecticut State Holstein Show".
  - James Marshall Osborn (Box 1, Folder 9)
    1958 Nov-Dec, New England Holstein Bulletin
    "Connecticut Notes and Quotes".
  - James Marshall Osborn (Box 1, Folder 10)
    1959 May
    Form letter to family explaining results of 1959
    herd dispersal.
  - James Marshall Osborn (Box 1, Folder 11)
    n.d.
    "Give Me a Herd of Holsteins" (to the tune of "Deep
    in the Heart of Texas").
  - Marie-Louise Osborn (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Autograph MSS
    "Notes about Whirlwind Hill Farm in 1944" and
    notebook descriptions of settings, cows'
    personalities, and people at the farm.
  - 1942 Jan, New England States Holstein-Friesian Association Newsletter. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Reports on formation of Whirlwind Hill herd.
  - 1943 Dec 11, New England Homestead (Box 1, Folder 14)
    (reprint and 5 copies).
    Allen N. Crissey: "The Professor of Whirlwind
    Hill".
  - [1947] May 29, newspaper unknown (Box 1, Folder 15)
    "Holsteins Owned by Whirlwind Hill Farm Set
    Record".
    Accompanied by 2 other newspaper articles dated
    1948 Jan 26 and 14 Apr (year unknown).
  - 1948 Mar 2, Hartford Courant (Box 1, Folder 16)
    "State-raised Cattle Sought for Export".
  - 1948 May 7, Newtown Bee 1948 May 22, New England Homestead (Box 1, Folder 17)
    "Professor Merrill to Advise WW Hill Farms".
  - 1948 [Jun], New England Homestead (Box 1, Folder 18)
    "Heifer Classic Average $663.22".
    Accompanied by photo.
  - 1957 Jul-Aug, New England Holstein Bulletin (Box 1, Folder 19)
    (reprint)
    "New Type of 'Co-op' in Connecticut".
  - 1957 Sep 27, Kiwanigram (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Mention that Olympian was crowned Grand Champion
    bull of Eastern States Exposition during the
    previous week.
  - 1958 May 24, Holstein-Friesian World (Box 1, Folder 21)
    "Holstein Hunting in Connecticut, with Ted".
  - [1958 or afterwards], [Conn. State (Holstein) Assn. (Newsletter)] (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Fred M Nichols: "Conn. Holstein Highlights".
  - [before 1959], Holstein-Friesian Assn. of America, news release. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    "WW Hill Farm...has qualified for the Progressive
    Breeder's Award".
  - 1959 Jul 19, New Haven Register (Box 1, Folder 24)
    "Yale Professor, who Auctioned off Prize Cows, Sees
    Federal Order Dooming Connecticut Herds".
    Accompanied by a typed draft of the story.
  - 1959 Nov-Dec, New England Holstein Bulletin (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Howard Davis: "Connecticut Notes"
  - 1965 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Miscellaneous newspaper clippings on controversy
    about selecting a golf course site for Wallingford.
    WW Hill was a considered site.
    Accompanied by TLS from Peter Powers Hale to JMO,
    1966 Jan 12.
  - 1971 May-Jun, New England Holstein Bulletin (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Laura B. Dugan: "Birth and Development of the
    New England States Holstein-Friesian Association".
  - 1971 Nov-Dec, New England Holstein Bulletin. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Mention of JMO, former owner of WW Hill, who was
    met by the (unknown) columnist at "the sale".
    Accompanied by 1972 Nov-Dec article from New England
    Holstein Bulletin. Attributes JMO with establishing
    the Allen Crissey Award, anonymously, in 1954.
  - 3 photos of the farm (Box 1, Folder 29)
    1959 May, New England Selective Breeding Assn.
    Newsletter, Cover photo
    n.d., The Record Journal
    1953 Sep, Connecticut Farmer, Cover photo of WW
    Hill barns.
  - Ariel, 1955 Apr 25, Hoard's Dairyman (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Cover photo of Whirlhill Q Rag Apple Ariel and
    twins.
    Accompanied by 1957 Sep Holstein News article,
    "Transplanted Ariel Blossoms Anew" and other
    articles about Ariel.
  - Kingpin, 1967 Nov 25, Hostein-Friesian World. (Box 1, Folder 31)
    Cover photo and article about Whirlhill Kingpin.
    Accompanied by another H-F World article (n.d.),
    "Whirlhill Kingpin, A First in USDA History", by
    Bennet Cassell. Also, advertising about Kingpin
    pulled from various issues of H-F World, 1967-73.
  - The Kingpin Issue, 1973 Feb 10, Holstein-Friesian World (Box 1, Folder 32)
    James M. Osborn: "Whirlhill Kingpin - His 'Reason
    for Being' as Related by his Breeder".
    2 copies of article and draft.
  - Letters to JMO concerning the Kingpin issue. (Box 1, Folder 33)
    Horace Backus, 1973 Feb 13, Holstein Sales Manager
    Bob Hastings, 1973 Feb 2, Holstein-Friesian World
    Mrs. Marion Seifert, 1973 Feb 10, Middletown farmer
  - New Haven County Farm Bureau, 1947 Apr 7. (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Notice of talk to be given by James G.[sic] Osborn.
  - Osborndale Dispersal, 1957 May 8-9 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    Advertisement in Holstein-Friesian World.
  - Wesleyan University Alumnus, 1942 May (Box 1, Folder 36)
    Segment on JMO in class notes, mentioning the
    farm his civil defense work, and career.
  - The Whirlhill Legacy (Box 1, Folder 37)
    Advertisements; acounts of progeny at other farms.
  - "Zephyrs from Whirlwind Hill" (Box 1, Folder 38)
    Newsletters: 11/41, 2/42, 4/42
    Calendars: 1942-47, 1949
    2 season's greetings cards
- Files relating to dairy farming, Series II
  - New England Holstein-Friesian membership, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    1943, 1944
  - JMO's notes on purebred advantages, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - JMO's notes on alternative marketing systems: (Box 2, Folder 3)
    purebred bonus.
  - Plan to loan 4-H youth members calves. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "Golden Guernsey Propaganda". Clipped by JMO, c. 1943-45. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: JMO to Brock-Hall Producers Association, 1941-46. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Whirlwind Hill Farm Barn Handlist, 1944 Mar 16. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - JMO's proposal for an Eastern Breeder's Cooperative. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Proposed pedigree livestock insurance plan, 1946. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Connecticut Wholesale Milk Producer's Council, 1948. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - JMO's notes on Brisish Breeding of Holsteins. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - $500 Guarantee Plan. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Whirlwind Hill Farm cattle inventory, 1943-49. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Dispersal record
  - Sorenson farm inventory, 1947. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Farm personnel: Warren Anderson, herd manager, 1958-59. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Farm personnel: Ralph Bunker, 1959. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence with Elmer Loemker, designer of JMO's Holstein Handbook, 1947-48. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence between JMO and Robert E. Minthorn, 1943-51 (Cloverdale Farms). (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "Bred Heifer Classic" sales, 1945 and 1946. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Whirlwind Hill Farm, field work. 1949-50. (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Correspondence, Series III
  - John W. Bartlett, Chairman, Rutgers Department of Dairy Industry, and James Marshall Osborn. 1945-53 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - John W. Bartlett and James Marshall Osborn. 1954 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - John W. Bartlett and James Marshall Osborn. 1955 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - John W. Bartlett and James Marshall Osborn. 1956-57 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Leo R. Blanding, Herd Analysis and Registry, Holstein-Friesian Association of America, and James Marshall Osborn. 1943-45 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Leo R. Blanding and James Marshall Osborn. 1946 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Leo R. Blanding and James Marshall Osborn. 1947-48 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Leo R. Blanding and James Marshall Osborn. 1949-50 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Leo R. Blanding and James Marshall Osborn. 1951-55 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Allen N. Crissey, Fieldman, Holstein-Friesian Association, and James Marshall Osborn. 1941-44 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Allen N. Crissey and James Marshall Osborn. 1945. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Allen N. Crissey and James Marshall Osborn. 1946. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Allen N. Crissey and James Marshall Osborn. 1947-48. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Laura Dugan, office secretary, New England Holstein- Friesian Association, and James Marshall Osborn. 1944. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Laura Dugan and James Marshall Osborn. 1945 (Jan-Jun) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Laura Dugan and James Marshall Osborn. 1945 (Jul-Dec) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Laura Dugan and James Marshall Osborn. 1946-48 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Glen M. Householder, Director of Extension Service, Holstein-Friesian Association, and James Marshall Osborn. 1941-44 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Glen M. Householder and James Marshall Osborn. 1945-46 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Glen M. Householder and James Marshall Osborn. 1947-49 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Gertrude and R. DeWitt Mallary, and James Marshall Osborn. 1941-44 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Gertrude and R. DeWitt Mallary, and James Marshall Osborn. 1945 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Gertrude and R. DeWitt Mallary, and James Marshall Osborn. 1946-48 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Gertrude and R. DeWitt Mallary, and James Marshall Osborn. 1949-56 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Arthur Petersen and James Marshall Osborn. 1944-46 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Arthur Petersen and James Marshall Osborn. 1947-48 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Arthur Petersen and James Marshall Osborn. 1949-52 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Arthur Petersen and James Marshall Osborn. 1953-57 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - William A. Prescott, associate editor (?) of Holstein- Friesian World, and James Marshall Osborn. 1942-44 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - William A. Prescott and James Marshall Osborn. 1945 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - William A. Prescott and James Marshall Osborn. 1946 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - William A. Prescott and James Marshall Osborn. 1947-52 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - William E. Reed and James Marshall Osborn. 1944-47 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - William E. Reed and James Marshall Osborn. 1948-50 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - William E. Reed and James Marshall Osborn. 1951-52 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - William E. Reed and James Marshall Osborn. 1953 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - William E. Reed and James Marshall Osborn. 1954-56 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - William E. Reed and James Marshall Osborn. 1957-66 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Mrs. Elgie Larson Streeter, Assistant Director, Extension Service, Holstein-Friesian Association, also collaborator with JMO on "The Holstein Handbook', and James Marshall Osborn. 1942-44. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Mrs. Elsie L. Streeter and James Marshall Osborn. 1945 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Mrs. Elsie L. Streeter and James Marshall Osborn. 1946 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Mrs. Elsie L. Streeter and James Marshall Osborn. 1947 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Dewees W. Dilworth and James Marshall Osborn. 1944-55 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Richard Kellogg, General Manger, Central Ohio Breeding Association, and James Marshall Osborn. 1953 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Senator Francis Maloney and James Marshall Osborn. 1941-43 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Fred M. Nichols and James Marshall Osborn. 1943-45 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - M. B. Nichols (Nick) and James Marshall Osborn. 1943-45 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - The Rev. Victor M. Rhein and James Marshall Osborn. 1948-58 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Organizational Involvement, Series IV
  - Invitations and programs. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Includes 4-H Recognition Dinner program at which
    JMO was toastmaster, and his notes for that
    occasion, 1948 May 13. Also JMO's notes for his
    speech at Holstein Convention, 1957.
  - Connecticut Dairymen's Association. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Report of the Proceedings of the 66th annual
    Convention. 1947 Jan 21-22.
  - New England Holstein Bulletin. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    8 issues: 1944 Jun-Jul through 1945 Jul-Aug.
  - New England Holstein Bulletin. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    "Holsteins are Our Business", column from many
    issues. Accompanied by rough drafts by JMO.
  - Breeder's Gazette. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Articles by JMO, and correspondence.
  - Miscellaneous committee and meeting notes. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - "The Holstein Handbook". (Box 7, Folder 7)
    4 copies including 1 annotated copy.
    Accompanied by photocopy of TLS from JMO to
    Glen Householder, 1947 Sep 3.
  - Byers Cellars, Unlimited. (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Advertising and Photography., Series V
  - Whirlwind Hill Farm advertisements. (Box 7, Folder 9)
    New England Holstein Bulletin, Connecticut Farmer,
    and Holstein-Friesan World. 1943-49.
  - Whirlwind Hill Farm advertisements. (Box 7, Folder 10)
    Holstein-Friesian World, New England Holstein
    Bulletin, various show programs. 1950-59.
  - Whirlwind Hill Farm advertisements. (Box 7, Folder 11)
    American Agriculturist. 1944-46. Includes
    correspondence regarding advertising.
  - Advertisements, miscellaneous. (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - JMO and Princess Louisa Posch, 1941. Framed photo. (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - JMO. Miscellaneous photographs. (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Photography, Series VI
  - Early years at Whirlwind Hill Farm. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Farm views, 1948. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Field Day, 1948. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Whirlwind Hill Farm Dispersal, 1949 Apr 2. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Wallingford map. Accompanied by aerial view of Whirlwind Hill Farm (?) and another photograph of farm. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Apollo and others. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous photographs of the farm and cows. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Also in box: album with photographs and advertisements, and box with two trays of colour slides.
- Business Records and Documents, Series VII
  - Dispersals
    - 1949 Dispersal - Whirlwind Hill Farm. (Box 10, Folder 1)
      1949 Apr 2. 2 annotated catalogues.
    - 1949 Dispersal - Whirlwind Hill Farm. (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Miscellaneous advertisements, newspaper and
      magazine articles about dispersal. Included is
      New England Holstein Bulletin of May-Jun 1949
      which featured the dispersal as its cover story.
    - "Cattle-log of the Gracious Ladies of Osborndale Dispersal". 1957 May 8-9. JMO's copy. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - "Osborndale Dispersal Makes History", Holstein- Friesian World. 1957 Jun 8 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - 1959 Dispersal - Whirlwind Hill Farm. 1959 May 28. (Box 10, Folder 5)
      Official copy of catalogue.
    - 1959 Dispersal - Whirlwind Hill Farm. (Box 10, Folder 6)
      1959 May 28. "Marked addenda for Horace Backus".
    - 1959 Dispersal - Whirlwind Hill Farm. (Box 10, Folder 7)
      1959 May 28. Annotated copy [JMO's?].
    - 1959 Dispersal - Whirlwind Hill Farm. (Box 10, Folder 8)
      1959 May 28. 1 copy.
    - 1959 Dispersal - Whirlwind Hill Farm. (Box 10, Folder 9)
      1959 Jun 5. Record of auction from Granger
      Sales Co.
    - 1959 Dispersal - Whirlwind Hill Farm. (Box 10, Folder 10)
      1959 May 28. Newspaper articles, advertisements,
      news releases, circulars dealing with dispersal.
    - Included in box: photograph album with pictures from dispersal, advertisements, and article from Holstein-Friesian World, 1959 Jun 27. (Box 10)
  - Leases
    - Bartholomew Lease. 1941-43. (Box 10, Folder 11)
      Lease of Harriet E. Bartholomew's farm to James
      M. Osborn.
    - Sorenson Lease. 1941-47. (Box 10, Folder 12)
      Lease of Elmer Sorenson's farm to James M. Osborn.
    - Rickard Lease. 1949. (Box 10, Folder 13)
      Lease of James M. Osborn's farm to Dean Rickard.
    - Clementel Lease. 1959-63. (Box 10, Folder 14)
      Lease of James M. and Marie-Louise Osborn's farm
      to James Clementel and Roland Clememtal.
  - Cattle
    - "Whirlhill" Prefix Certificate, 1951. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Whirlhill Holsteins - Inventory and accounts. 1949-51. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Whirlhill Holsteins - Inventory and accounts. 1952. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Whirlhill Holsteins - Inventory and accounts. 1954. (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Queen's Majesty Partnership. 1956. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Cattle accounts. 1949-54. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Cattle accounts. 1957. (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Holstein Activity Index by States. (1944 and 1945 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      compared to 1941-43 base).
    - Capital gains ruling for cattle sales. (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Purebreds - income tax status. 1955. (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Certificate of Herd Improvement Registry for Whirlwind Hill Farm. 1952 Mar, Holstein-Friesian Association of America. (Box 11, Folder 11)